啊
Agh!
刚好是一分五十二秒 太好了
Exactly 1 minute 52 seconds. That's excellent.
《007系列之俄罗斯之恋》
(威尼斯国际象棋圣手锦标赛)
将军
Check.
马吃象
Knight takes bishop.
(马上要召见你)
王走向车二
King to rook two.
王后走到王四
Queen to king four.
恭喜你 很杰出的一步
My congratulations, sir. A brilliant coup.
暹罗斗鱼 迷人的生物
Siamese fighting fish. Fascinating creatures.
勇敢 但总括来说 很笨 对 他们很笨
Brave, but, on the whole, stupid. Yes, they're stupid.
除了是这里的一条
Except for the occasional one, such as we have here,
他让其他两条自相残杀
who lets the other two fight...
自己则静心等待
while he waits.
等到活下来的那条筋疲力尽 无法自卫
Waits until the survivor is so exhausted that he cannot defend himself.
然后 跟幽灵一样 他就出击
Then, like SPECTRE, he strikes.
这种相似之处十分有趣
I find the parallel amusing.
组织安排你从俄国远道而来
Our organisation did not arrange for you to come over from the Russians
并非是为了享乐的 三号
just for amusement, Number Three.
进来吧 克朗斯汀
Come in, Kronsteen.
坐下吧 三号 我们听听 五号的计策
Sit down, Number Three, while we listen to what Number Five has devised for us.
希望策划科主管克朗斯汀的成就
I hope his efforts as director of planning continue...
会像他在西洋棋的成就般卓越
to be as successful as his chess.
一定会的
They will be.
根据你的指示 我为幽灵党计划
As you instructed, I've planned for SPECTRE
从俄国偷取新式的列克托解码器
to steal from the Russians their new Lektor decoding machine.
为此我们需要俄国密码部 一位驻土耳其的女成员
For this we need the services of the Russian Cryptograph Section in Turkey
以及英国情报机构的协助
and the help of the British Secret Service.
当然 英俄双方都不会知道 他们是在替我们工作的
Neither the Russians nor the British will be aware that they are working for us.
三号 你的部门准备好 执行克朗斯汀的指令了没有?
Number Three, is your section ready to carry out the directives?
准备好了 我们会根据他的计划 组织行动
Yes, the operation will be organised according to Kronsteen's plan.
我从伊斯坦堡的俄国领事馆中 挑选了适当人选
I have selected a girl from the Russian Consulate in Istanbul.
她既能干 又合作 对国家忠心耿耿
She's capable, cooperative, and her loyalty to the state is beyond question.
你确定她相信你仍然是 苏联情报机关的行动组首脑吗?
You're sure she believes you're still head of operations for Soviet Intelligence?
她不可能会知道 我已经加入了幽灵党
It's most unlikely she would know I'm now working for SPECTRE.
莫斯科严守着我脱党的秘密 只有主席团的小数成员知道
Moscow has kept my defection secret from everyone but the presidium.
为了你着想 但愿如此吧
For your sake, I hope so.
克朗斯汀 你确定这个计划万无一失?
Kronsteen, you're sure this plan is foolproof?
是的 我已经考虑到对方的 对抗手段
Yes, because I have anticipated every possible variation of countermove.
何以见得英国情报机构的首领 M
But what makes you think that M...
会同意你的计划 并出手相助?
will oblige you by falling in with your plan?
因为这明显是个陷阱
For the simple reason that this is so obviously a trap.
我认为英国人的心理就是 视陷阱为挑战
My reading of the British mentality is that they always treat a trap as a challenge.
无论如何 他们都不会放过 任何一个得到解码器的机会
And they couldn't possibly pass up the chance of getting the Lektor decoder.
他们一直希望能得到一个
They have wanted one for years.
你说的都可能是事实 还有呢?
All that you say could be true. What else?
还有 幽灵党也许有机会
SPECTRE will probably have the chance of a personal revenge
为诺博士的死报仇
for the killing of our operative Dr No,
对于这种任务
because the man the British will almost certainly use on a mission of this sort
英国肯定会派詹姆斯邦德来应付
would be their agent, James Bond.
在他死前 尽情折磨他 让他受尽侮辱
Let his death be a particularly unpleasant and humiliating one.
好 我要马上将计划付诸行动
Good. I'll put my plan into operation straight away.
绝对不会失败的
And there will be no failure.
赶快
Hurry.
欢迎来到幽灵岛 我们很荣幸 希望你的旅途愉快
Welcome to SPECTRE Island. I hope you had a pleasant flight.
时间有限 我需要的人准备好了没?
My time is limited. Is the man I requested ready?
他的档案  好
His dossier. Good.
"唐纳德葛兰 杀人犯"
Donald Grant, convicted murderer.
"1960年越狱，1962年招募于谭吉尔"
Escaped Dartmoor Prison in 1960, recruited in Tangier in 1962.
好极了 他人在哪?
Excellent. Where is he now?
在湖边 把他带到我的办公室
At the lake. Bring him to my office, will you?
带我到湖边去 穿过训练区就是了
Take me to the lake. Through the training area.
葛兰是精英份子之一 嗜杀成狂 是一流人才
Grant's one of our best men. Homicidal paranoiac, superb material.
虽然手法比较残忍 但是他对训练和教化 都有卓越的反应
His response to our training and indoctrination have been remarkable.
希望你认可我们这里的工作
I hope our work here meets with your approval.
训练是有帮助 但是实战经验才是最重要的
Training is useful, but there is no substitute for experience.
我同意 我们也有用活人靶子的
I agree. We use live targets as well.
叫他来  葛兰!
Call him. Grant!
他蛮强壮的 要他在一天内 到伊斯坦堡向我报到
He seems fit enough. Have him report to me in Istanbul in 24 hours.
(总领事馆)
[俄罗斯语]
[ Russian ]
[土耳其语]
[ Turkish ]
国家安全局下士 塔坦妮雅罗曼诺娃报到
Corporal of State Security Tatiana Romanova.
进来吧
Come in.
你知道我是谁吗?
You know who I am?
克莱普上校 情报科行动科首领
Colonel Klebb, head of operations for SMERSH.
我在莫斯科英国解码室工作时 曾见过你一次
I saw you once in Moscow, when I worked for the English decoding room.
你有跟领事馆的人提到 你来这里的事吗?
Did you tell anyone you were coming here?
不 电报上说 我知道 是我发出的
No, the message... Yes, yes, I know. I sent it.
你的工作记录很杰出
Your work record is excellent.
国家以你为荣 谢谢你 上校同志
The state is proud of you. Thank you, Comrade Colonel.
把夹克脱下
Take off your jacket.
转个圈圈
Turn around.
你很漂亮
You're a fine-looking girl.
坐下吧
Sit down.
你曾受芭蕾舞训练
I see you trained for the ballet.
但是我比规定的高度高了一寸
But I grew an inch over the regulation height, and so...
你曾经有三个情人?
And then you have had three lovers.
干嘛要问这些私人问题呢?
What is the purpose of such an intimate question?
你来这里不是要发问 你忘了自己在跟谁说话!
You're not here to ask questions. You forget to whom you are speaking.
那时我在恋爱 若你不是在恋爱呢?
I was in love. And if you were not in love?
我想这得看男方是谁了
I suppose that would depend on the man.
答得很明智 例如是这个男人
Sensible answer. This man, for instance.
不知道 若他既体贴又文明 我也许愿意
I cannot tell. Perhaps if he was kind and kulturny.
我挑选了你进行一次重要任务
Corporal, I have selected you for a most important assignment.
目的在向敌人发放假消息
Its purpose is to give false information to the enemy.
若你成功 可获擢升
If you complete it successfully, you will be promoted.
从现在开始 你要对他言听计从
From now on, you will do anything he says.
若我拒绝呢? 你休想活着离开这里
And if I refuse? Then you will not leave this room alive.
我服从你的命令 好 这是你的指示
I will obey your orders. Good. Now, these are your instructions.
你到这里来向我报到 然而领事馆的人不可以知道我在伊斯坦堡
You report to me here, but the consulate security man must not know anything.
这次任务远超他的职责范围 我会守口如瓶的
This is classified far above his level. I will say nothing...
若你敢多言 我会毙了你
If you do, you will be shot.
过来吧 亲爱的
Come, come, my dear.
你很幸运 能获选执行这件简单轻松的任务
You're very fortunate to have been chosen for such a simple, delightful duty.
你就是我们说的爱情特工
A real labour of love, as we say.
来自俄罗斯的爱
"From Russia With Love"
这真是好运动 你说什么?
Great sport, this. What did you say?
我说划艇是很好的运动
I said it's great sport, this punting.
我绝对同意 我也许会为此而放弃高尔夫球
I couldn't agree with him more. I may even give up golf for it.
真的吗?
Really?
也不是
Not quite.
是别的醋坛子留下的战绩吗?
Souvenir from another jealous woman?
此后我从没对女人掉头不顾过
Yes. But I haven't turned my back on one since.
对不起 什么?
Excuse me. What?
衬衫给我 怎么了?
Give me my shirt. What's going on?
我要打电话 但是我们还没吃饭呢
I have to make a phone call. But we haven't eaten yet.
我饿坏了
I'm starving.
说吧 我是邦德
Come in, Univex. James Bond here. Over.
他整个早上都在找你 你在哪?
He's been asking for you all morning. Where in the world are you, James?
我在重温一件旧案子
Well, I've just been reviewing an old case.
现在我成了旧案子吗?  是公司
So I'm an old case now, am I? It's the office.
跟他说我在回来途中 他才不是呢
Tell him I'm on my way, will you? He is not on his way.
你听话 我们改天再聚吧
Sylvia, behave. We'll do this again some other time soon.
聚什么?你上次这样说过后 就到了牙买加了
Do what? Last time you said that, you went off to Jamaica.
我们已半年没见了
I haven't seen you for six months.
我一小时后回来 我会告诉他的了
I'll be there in an hour. I'll tell him.
你的旧案子很有趣呢
Hey. Your old case sounds interesting, James.
我一个半小时后才到
Make that an hour and a half.
说起午餐
Now, about that lunch.
下一个奇迹就是
For my next miracle, I...
若他能解释今天往哪跑了才是奇迹
It'll be a miracle if he can explain where he's been all day.
我从没听过塔坦妮雅罗曼诺娃这个名字
But I've never even heard of a Tatiana Romanova.
很荒谬吧 简直是疯了
Ridiculous, isn't it? It's absolutely crazy.
女孩子的确会爱上明星照片
Of course, girls do fall in love with pictures of film stars.
但是俄国的密码员 不应该爱上英国特工的照片
But not a Russian cipher clerk with a file photo of a British agent.
除非她是疯子
Unless she's mental.
不 这是陷阱
No, it's some sort of trap.
很明显 这是陷阱 诱饵就是全新的列克托密码机
Obviously it's a trap, and the bait is a cipher machine, a brand-new Lektor.
中央情报局已经找了它一年了
A Lektor, no less. The CIA's been after one of those for years.
我们也是
Yes, so have we.
她跟土耳其T分局的头目 克林贝接触
When she contacted Kerim Bey, head of Station T in Turkey,
说要脱党 并愿意把解码器交给我们
and told him she wanted to defect, she said she'd turn it over to us.
条件是
On one condition.
你要到伊斯坦堡去 护送她和解码器回英国
That you went out to Istanbul and brought her and the machine back to England.
这是克林给她拍的快照
Here's a snapshot Kerim managed to get of her.
虽然我对密码学的了解不深
I don't know too much about cryptography,
但是列克托可以解开他们的绝密信号
but a Lektor could decode their top secret signals.
整件事实在太难以置信了 很有可能是真的
The whole thing's so fantastic it just could be true.
我也想过
That had occurred to me.
最近俄国人没耍什么花招
Besides, the Russians haven't been up to any tricks recently.
最近我比较清闲
Well, really, I'm not too busy at the moment, sir.
早上八点半的机位已经替你订好了
You're booked on the 8.30 plane in the morning.
不要错过任何可以取到解码器的机会
If there's any chance of us getting a Lektor, we must look into it.
倘若她跟我见面时 我不符合她的要求呢?
Suppose when she meets me in the flesh I don't come up to expectations?
你必须达到她的要求
Just see that you do.
钱班霓小姐 请装备员进来
Miss Moneypenny, ask the equipment officer to come in, please.
Q装配了一个很帅气的行李
Q Branch has put together a smart-Iooking piece of luggage for us.
所有编号00的人员 都会被分派到一个
We're issuing this to all double-0 personnel.
一个普通的黑色皮箱 两边分别拥有二十发弹药
An ordinary black leather case with 20 rounds of ammunition here and here.
把顶端挪开 就会看见弹药
Now, if you take the top off, you'll find the ammunition inside.
这边有一柄平伸的匕首
In the side here, a flat throwing knife.
按下这个按钮就行
Press that button there, and out she comes.
箱子内备有AR7可折叠的狙击手来福枪
Inside the case, you'll find an AR7 folding sniper's rifle.
点25口径 配备红外线望远镜
.25 calibre, with an infrared telescopic sight.
这条带子藏有五十个一镑金币 每边二十五个
Then, if you pull out these straps, inside are 50 gold sovereigns, 25 in either side.
小心看清楚 这是一罐滑石粉
Now, watch very carefully. An ordinary tin of talcum powder.
里面其实是催泪弹 它这样黏着箱子旁边
Inside, a tear-gas cartridge. That goes in the case against the side here.
它有磁性 不会掉下来 关上箱子
It's magnetised, so it won't fall. Shut the case.
一般来说 要打开箱子 你把钩子往两边推
Normally, to open a case like that, you move the catches to the side.
这样催泪弹就会在你面前爆炸
If you do, the cartridge will explode in your face.
为了防止爆炸 将钩子横移
Now, to stop the cartridge exploding, turn the catches horizontally, like that.
然后按照惯例打开
Then, open normally.
你试试看
Now you try it.
把钩子这样转  对了
Turn the catches like that. That's right.
然后按照惯例打开
And open ordinarily.
明白了吗?  应该明白了
You got it? Yes, I think so.
没别的事了吧?  没有了 谢谢你
Is that all, sir? Yes, thanks very much.
这份圣诞礼物真厉害 不过我用不着
Nasty little Christmas present. But I shouldn't need it on this assignment.
带着他上路吧 祝你好运 007
All the same, take it with you. Good luck, 007.
谢谢 长官
Thank you, sir.
"再次深入虎穴了"
"Once more unto the breach, dear friends."
还有一张机票 你真走运 我从没到过伊期坦堡
And one plane ticket. Lucky man. I've never been to Istanbul.
你从没到过伊期坦堡? 没有
You've never been to Istanbul? No.
在那里 博斯普鲁斯的月色令人陶醉
Where the moonlight on the Bosphorus is irresistible?
也许有天我会让你带我去 我已经试过其他一切了
Maybe I should get you to take me there someday. I've tried everything else.
亲爱的钱班霓 我对其他女人不屑一顾
Darling Moneypenny, you know I never even look at another woman.
真的吗?
Really, James?
让我把世界的奥秘告诉你
Let me tell you the secret of the world.
钱班霓小姐 叫007把照片留下
Miss Moneypenny, ask 007 to leave the photograph.
他一定可以把那位女士认出
I'm sure he'll recognise the lady when he sees her.
(带着爱意来的苏俄人)
祝你好运 再见
Good luck. Ciao.
再见
Ciao.
伦敦 你的飞机刚抵达
Hello, London. Your flight PA1 just landed Istanbul.
邦德先生
Mr Bond.
克林贝派了车来接你 好
Kerim Bey sent a car for you, sir. Fine.
可以借一根火柴用吗? 我用打火机的
Can I borrow a match? I use a lighter.
那就更好了 直到它们坏掉
It's better still. Until they go wrong.
一点不错 我去开车来
Exactly. I'll get the car, sir.
克林贝建议你到饭店前 先跟他见面
Kerim Bey suggested that you see him before going to the hotel.
你方便吗?  好的
Would that be convenient? Fine.
让别人跟踪是这里的惯例吧
I suppose it's customary to have people tailing you in these parts.
是的 今天值班的是雪铁龙H31854
Today it's Citroen H31854 on duty. Oh, yes.
他们是替俄国人办事的保加利亚人 我们互相跟踪
Bulgarians working for the Russians. They follow us, we follow them.
大家互有默契 那真友善
It's a sort of understanding we have. That's very friendly.
朋友 进来吧
Ah, my friend, come in, come in.
很高兴看见你 欢迎来到伊斯坦堡
Glad to see you. Welcome to Istanbul.
谢谢你的车子 但这把我们两个连系起来
Thank you for sending the car. But it does rather tie you in with me.
这里是巴尔干半岛 跟俄国人玩游戏的方式有点不同
You're in the Balkans now. The game with the Russians is played differently.
在日常事务方面 互相派车辆跟踪对方并不困难
For routine matters, we don't make it too difficult to keep a tab on each other.
你的司机已经跟我说了 这个年轻人蛮聪明的
So I gathered from your chauffeur. He's a rather intelligent young man.
这是应该的 他是我儿子
He should be. He's my son.
要咖啡吗? 不太甜也不太苦
Coffee? Medium sweet.
要两杯 不太甜也不太苦
Two medium sweet.
他也是我儿子
He also is my son.
所有主要雇员都是我儿子 家族关系是这行的最佳保障
All my key employees are my sons. Blood is the best security in this business.
你在这里的事业一定很庞大 雇员数目为全土耳其之冠
You must have quite an establishment. Biggest family payroll in Turkey.
对一个马戏团的前杂技人来说 算是不俗了
Not bad for a man who used to break chains and bend bars in a circus.
不如谈谈你的事业 M认为我是在浪费时间
But let's talk about your business. M thinks I'm wasting my time here.
我也是这样想 我这个老朋友
And so do I. This is an old friend of mine.
嗅出有状况了 也许吧
And it tells me something smells. Maybe.
但是若有机会获得列克托
But if there's a chance of getting a Lektor...
告诉我在哪可以跟这女孩联络?
Now you tell me. Where can I contact this girl?
她说她会自行安排 你得耐心等待
She said she would make her own arrangements. You'll have to wait.
谢谢
Thank you.
朋友 若你真的要听我的意见
My friend, if you really want my advice,
你应该在伊斯坦堡欢度几天 然后回家
you should spend a few pleasant days with us here in Istanbul, then go home.
詹姆斯邦德 我预留了房间的 已经准备好了
James Bond, I have a reservation. Your room is ready.
32号房
Number 32.
邦德先生的32号房  希望你满意
32 for Mr Bond. Hope you enjoy your stay.
谢谢
Thank you.
还有其他吩咐吗?  只有这个 谢谢
Will there be anything else, sir? Only this. Thank you.
谢谢你 先生
Thank you, sir.
我是邦德 这间房子不太适合 很抱歉
Mr Bond here. I'm afraid the room won't do.
床太小了 请等等 你听到了没有?
The bed's too small. One moment, sir. Did you hear that?
告诉他房间都满了 只剩下结婚套房
Tell him that's all there is. Unless he would like the bridal suite.
很抱歉 没有空房了 除了结婚套房
I'm sorry, sir. That's all we have available, except the bridal suite.
让我看看 也许我会喜欢的
Well, let's have a look at it. I may like it.
服务员会带你看看 他马上就上去
The porter will show it to you. He will be up immediately.
很好
Good.
做得好 俄国不怀疑英国还会怀疑谁?
Good work. Who can the Russians suspect but the British?
伊斯坦堡的冷战 很快就会炽热起来
The Cold War in Istanbul will not remain cold very much longer.
克林贝
Ali Kerim Bey...
克林贝 嗯
Ali Kerim Bey. Mm.
克林贝
Ali Kerim Bey.
今早见到我不高兴吗?
You are not glad to see me this morning?
大喜过望
Overjoyed.
我再也无法取悦你了吗?
I no longer please you?
别乱动!
Be still.
要回到做苦工的地方了
Back to the salt mines.
小心处理那些文件
Careful with those papers.
是谁赢了?  我有客人
Well, who won? I had visitors.
外墙装有计时的水下爆破弹 要把书桌前的我轰掉
Limpet mine on the wall outside. Timed to catch me at my desk.
幸好我在沙发上休息了几分钟
But, by good fortune, I was relaxing on the settee for a few moments.
那个女孩歇斯底里地离开了 她觉得你太暴力了吧?
The girl left in hysterics. Found your technique too violent?
我不懂为何要破坏休战协定 俄国人不像会这样破坏和平的
I can't understand this sudden breach of the truce. It's unlike the Russians.
太鲁莽了 这该跟我的到访有关
Most inconsiderate. My visit might have something to do with it.
试试看找出原因吧
Let's try and find out.
把它关起来
Close up afterwards.
这里的环境很不错呢
Quite a place.
1600年前 君士坦丁皇 兴建了这个水库
The Emperor Constantine built it as a reservoir 1600 years ago.
真的吗?
Really?
拿着
Here.
这是我每天的运动 早上十一点和下午三点
My daily exercise: At eleven in the morning and three in the afternoon.
把它绑起来 好吗?
Tie her up, will you?
小心头部
Mind your head now.
在俄国领事馆下面
Underneath the Russian Consulate.
是英国海军送的
A present from your navy.
公共事务部进行勘察时 我们的朋友就被解雇了
Our friends were turned out by the Public Works Ministry.
因为繁忙的交通把地基动摇
The story was that the heavy traffic was shaking the foundations.
证实安全后 我就把这个装上了
By the time the place was declared safe, I had this installed.
M说你说得没错
I can see everything M said about you is right.
你知道我干嘛要留在这行业?
You know why I stay in this mad business?
因为卖地毯很苦闷
It could be that you find selling rugs a bore.
朋友 你真是深知我心
My friend, you should be a mind-reader.
主持者是军事情报机构主管 维斯里将军
Head of the table is General Vassili, director of Military Intelligence.
左边的是安全局主任 科斯洛夫斯基
On his left: Koslovski, Chief of Security.
对面的是俄国特工宝士
Opposite him: Benz, one of his agents.
我看不清另一个男人的面貌 那个在挨骂的人
I can't see the face of the other man, the one the general is shouting at.
他因为某些事而把那个人骂个狗血淋头
He's giving him a hell of a blowing up.
真可惜我们听不到谈话的内容
It's too bad we can't hear as well as see.
罗曼诺娃会进入这个房间吗?
Tell me. Does our girl Romanova ever come to this room?
她有时会把消息带来
Sometimes, with messages.
我看见另一个男人了
I can see the face of the other man now.
是柯里兰库!
Krilencu.
他回来了 另一个保加利亚杀人狂魔
So he's back. Another Bulgarian they use as a killer.
炸弹就是他放置的
Just the man for the limpet mine job.
我从前跟他有过节
I've had trouble with him before.
不过他离开伊斯坦堡已经一年了
But he's stayed out of Istanbul for over a year now.
看一下 你应该记得他的模样
Take a look. You should remember him.
这厮以杀人为乐
This man kills for pleasure.
很帅呢
Nice face.
等等 有个女孩进来了
Just a moment. A girl's just come in.
也许是罗曼诺娃 只有她才可以进来的
Probably Romanova. She's the only one who's allowed to.
她的样貌如何?
How does she look to you?
从这个角度看来 身材很不错
From this angle, things are shaping up nicely.
我要见她的本人
I'd like to see her in the flesh. Yes.
可以把这里的平面图给我吗?  我也希望可以
Could you get me a plan of that place? I wish I could.
一定有地方注册了这里的图样的
But there must be the original drawing somewhere.
我替你接洽吧
I'll get onto that.
我需要一点时间应付柯里兰库
Now, I need a little time to deal with this stinking Krilencu.
你今晚最好不要待在饭店里 来
It will be better if you didn't stay at the hotel tonight. Come.
我明白你干嘛要留着劳斯莱斯了
I see now why you keep the Rolls.
我其中一个儿子驾着它 后座坐着两个假人
One of my sons is driving it. With two dummies in the back.
往相反方向驶去 他们会跟上好几小时呢
In the opposite direction. They'll follow it for hours.
你会喜欢我的吉普赛朋友的
You'll like my Gypsy friends.
我利用他们 就像俄国人 利用保加利亚人一样
I use them like the Russians the Bulgars. It's created a blood feud between them.
柯里兰库
Hello, Krilencu.
[俄罗斯语]
[ Russian ]
我们来得不合时
It seems we've come on the wrong night.
两女爱上一男 要把对方除掉 一定要以吉普赛的方式解决
Two girls in love with the same man have threatened to kill each other.
我是他们的老朋友 可以留下来
As I'm an old friend of the family, we can stay.
他们请我们入席 希望你会用手吃饭吧
We're bidden to table. I hope you are good at eating with your fingers.
克林贝
Kerim Bey!
这是很名贵的
Raki. Filthy stuff.
快点!
Quick.
跟主人说他的招待实在太慇勤了
Tell our host his hospitality overwhelms me.
谢谢!
Thank you. Thank you.
不管怎么样 什么都别说 什么都别做
No matter what happens now, say and do nothing.
他说可否化干戈为玉帛 停止争斗
He's asking whether they will cease their blood feud.
让长老们决定谁可嫁给族长之子
The elders of the tribe will then decide who will marry the chief's son.
她说  你不用解说我也猜到了
She's saying... I think I got it without the subtitles.
谢谢!
Thank you!
抓到柯里兰库了没? 还没
Did you get Krilencu? No.
等等 拿来 谢谢
Just a minute. Here. Thank you.
你打得很好 我只是个糟老头
You fought well. I am nothing but a clumsy old man.
他们在向保加利亚伤者逼供
They're making one of the wounded Bulgars talk.
他们是冲着我而来的 干嘛要除掉我?
It was me they were after. Why would they want me out of the way?
明天我们得找到柯里兰库的巢穴
Tomorrow we will have to find Krilencu's hide-out.
这名贵的东西就由我来摆平吧
Meantime, I'll take care of this filthy stuff.
华拉感谢你救了他一命 你是他的儿子了
Vavra thanks you for saving his life. You are now his son.
谢谢
Thank you.
我想请求他阻止那些女孩打斗
I'd like to ask him a favour. Could he stop the girl fight?
他说你太心软 不能做真正吉普赛人 不过他会让你决定
Your heart is too soft to be a real Gypsy. But he lets you decide the matter.
好像我的麻烦还不够多似的
As if I didn't have enough problems.
华拉说由你来决定 你决定吧
Vavra said for you to decide. So decide.
她们都是你的
They're both yours.
这可需要花点时间了
This might take some time.
有没有到饭店替我收拾行李呢? 在座位上
Did you pick up the package? It's on the seat.
谢谢
Thank you.
柯里兰库曾两次要干掉我 下次他会成功的
Twice that Krilencu has tried to kill me. The third time he will succeed.
除非我先下手为强 我今晚就动手
Unless I get him first. And that I'll do tonight.
你的手伤了 不行 让我摆平他吧
Not with that arm, you won't. You'd better leave it to me.
我欠你的已经够多了 朋友之间说什么亏欠呢?
I'm already too much in your debt. How can a friend be in debt?
给你
Here.
红外线望远镜
Infrared lens.
嘘
Shh.
我的儿子
My sons.
他们会去按他的电铃 他有一个秘密的逃生天窗
They will ring his doorbell. He has a private escape hatch.
用这里来瞄准吧
Try this for size.
有发现吗?  还没有
Do you notice anything? Not yet.
那个安妮塔的小嘴很漂亮
She has a lovely mouth, that Anita.
我明白你的意思
Yes, I see what you mean.
不管有没有受伤 我都得亲自开枪
Arm or no arm, I have to pull that trigger.
若你觉得可以的话 记着 你只有一次机会
If you think you can. You've got one shot, remember.
已经足够了
It'll have to do.
快点 他来了
Quick. He's coming.
快点
Quick.
啊
Aah!
扯平了很多债
That pays many debts.
她应该把嘴巴闭起来的
She should have kept her mouth shut.
喂
Hello?
九点的时候 请送一人份的早餐上来
Breakfast for one at nine please.
无花果、优酪乳、黑咖啡 谢谢
Green figs, yoghurt, coffee very black. Thank you.
你看来很惊讶 我还以为你在等我
You look surprised. I thought you were expecting me.
你就是塔坦妮雅罗曼诺娃
So you are Tatiana Romanova?
我的朋友叫我坦妮雅
My friends call me Tania.
我的朋友叫我做詹姆斯邦德
Mine call me James Bond.
既然我们已正式介绍过了
Well, now that we've been properly introduced...
小心 我害怕手枪
Careful. Guns upset me.
对不起 我有点紧张
I'm sorry. I'm a bit upset myself.
你跟照片一模一样
You look just like your... your photograph.
你是我见过最漂亮的女孩之一
You're one of the most beautiful girls ever.
谢谢 不过我的嘴巴太大了
Thank you, but I think my mouth is too big.
大小刚好
No, it's the right size.
我觉得很适合
For me, that is.
是的
Yes.
它在这里吗?  什么?
Is it here? What?
列克托解码器
The decoding machine. Lektor.
我们一定要现在说吗?
Must we talk about it now?
还是在俄国领事馆里呢?
Or is it at the Russian Consulate?
是的
Yes.
我需要那个地方的平面图
Yes... I would need a plan of the place.
若你拿到的话 我们就装成游客 在圣索非亚清真寺见面
If you could get one, we could meet at the Saint Sophia mosque as tourists.
干嘛不晚一点才说呢?
Why don't you ask me that later?
你在找什么? 那道疤痕
Now what are you looking for? The scar.
从你的档案中 我对你了若指掌
You see? I know all about you from your file.
真的吗? 希望我不会让你失望
You do? Well, I hope you're not disappointed.
到天亮时
I will tell you...
我会告诉你
in the morning.
我们来到了 圣索非亚最有趣的角落
We are now approaching the most interesting corner of Saint Sophia.
这两条斑岩巨柱 是从埃及偷运进来的
Including these two great red porphyry columns, stolen and brought from Egypt.
在巨柱之前的 雪花石膏瓮是从贝尔加马带回来的
In front of them, alabaster urn was brought from Bergama,
那是一个历史名城 位于斯麦纳的附近
a famous historical city near Smyrna.
其源头追溯至 亚历山大大帝的年代
It dates back from the Alexander the Great period.
大概在1648年苏丹穆纳特四世 把它从贝尔加马带回来的
About 1648 Sultan Murad IV brought it from Bergama.
从前那是一个沐浴仪式用的喷泉 可以盛载一千升清水
It was used as an ablution fountain. It contains a thousand litres of water.
在沐浴泉后面
Right after the ablution fountain,
我们来到一条非常有趣的圆柱
we are going to a highly interesting column over there,
数个世纪以来 它被称为圣索非亚许愿柱
known for centuries as the Saint Sophia wishing column.
成千上万的人们 来这里许愿
Tens of thousands of people have wished here,
他们把右手的中指 放到柱洞中
putting their right hand and middle finger in the hole.
(讯号室 总办公室)
我可以保证 他不是我的手下干掉的
I promise you it wasn't one of my men who killed him.
他并非死于自然 但却省了我不少工夫
He didn't die of old age. All I know is that it saved me the job.
他一见到那女人 她已很明显的妥协了
Once he'd seen the girl, she was compromised, and so...
这并非他的死因
And he wasn't killed because of that.
这样说吧 伊斯坦堡是个暴力城市
Let's just say that Istanbul's a rough town.
看看坦妮雅的领事馆地图 跟你的平面图是否吻合
Let's see how Tania's map compares with your architect's plans.
这里是俄国领事馆的会议室 对了
This is conference room of the Russian Consulate. That checks.
这是通讯室 没错
And this here is the communication room. That's the same.
她每天二点至三点使用解码器
And she says she works there with the Lektor between two and three.
她如何把解码器弄给我们? 她由我决定 她对我言听计从
How is she gonna get the machine to us? She'll do anything I say.
什么都会做吗? 亲爱的詹姆斯 你没动过脑筋
Anything. My dear James, you're not using this.
听起来实在是太容易了 我们甚至不知道她有没有说谎
It all sounds too easy. We don't even know if she's telling the truth.
我打算找出真相 在哪? 在饭店里吗?
I intend to find out. Where? In the hotel?
她不会再到那里去 她说太危险了
No. She won't go there again. She says it's too dangerous.
老掉牙的手段 先让你尝尝甜头 吊你的胃口
The old game. Give a wolf a taste, then keep him hungry.
朋友 她使你神魂颠倒了
My friend, she's got you dangling.
没关系
That doesn't matter.
- 我只想要解码器 - 只想?
- All I want is that Lektor. - All?
你真的只想要解码器?
Are you sure that's all you want?
喂
Well...
风景真优美  我们必须马上离开这里
Lovely view. James, we must leave here now.
若那个特工揭发我跟你见面  别担心 他不会的
If that agent reports my meeting you... Don't worry. He won't.
你不明白 这样很危险的
But you don't understand the danger.
詹姆斯 看 笑一个
James, look up. Smile.
再拍一张 往后退
Another one. Further back.
那部机器 你关心的只是它 不是我
About the machine... That's all you are interested in. Not me.
先谈公事
Business first.
我知道 当你得到它之后
I know, once you have got what you want...
还没
I haven't got it yet.
但若你把机器的事告诉我 之后我们不见得要在办公时间内合作
But, afterwards, we won't always be working on the company's time.
你想要知道什么呢?
All right. What do you want to know?
对着它回答问题 悄悄说 但要清楚的
Talk into this. Answer my questions quietly, but clearly.
那部机器有多大呢?
How large is the machine?
就像一部打字机
Like... like a typewriter.
有多重?  大概十公斤吧
Weight? About ten kilos.
放在褐色箱子内 就像你的眼睛般
In a brown case. Brown like your eyes.
只谈公事 是自动校准还是用手操作的呢?
Keep it technical. Self-calibrating or manual?
两样都有 内置补助器
Both, with an in-built compensator.
我们可不可以 现在不行
James, couldn't we... Not now.
跟照相机说 有多少个键?
Talk into the camera. How many keys?
符号键还是密码键呢? 两样都要
Symbol or code keys? Both.
24个符号键 16个密码键
There are 24 symbols and 16 code keys.
把它插进狭长孔里 译本就会印在纸卷上
It is inserted in a slot and the message comes out in a paper roll
就会从另一边的狭长孔里出来 它的结构是
from another slot on the other side. The mechanism is...
詹姆斯 到英国后 我们会不断做爱吗?
Oh, James, James, will you make love to me all the time in England?
日以继夜都会 继续说它的结构
Day and night. Go on about the mechanism.
对 结构
Oh, yes, the mechanism.
有一次它进行维修时 我看过里面
Once, when it was being repaired, I saw the insides.
里面有很多穿孔的 我猜是铜片 有一小灯
There were many perforated discs, made I think of copper, with a small light.
你坦白告诉我 我跟那些西方女孩一样刺激吗?
Dushka, tell me the truth, am I as exciting as all those Western girls?
有一次我跟M在东京 经历了一次有趣的体验
Once, when I was with M in Tokyo, we had an interesting experience.
谢谢 钱班霓 这样可以了
Thank you, Miss Moneypenny. That's all, that's all.
晚一点
Later, later.
那些铜片和小灯 小灯!
Those copper discs and the light... Oh, the light, the light.
詹姆斯 靠近我 我有些话要私下告诉你
James, come closer. I want to whisper something.
继续吧 不是这样 说结构
Go on. No, not that. The mechanism.
钱班霓小姐 我知道你在听着的 请你记下这个电报
Miss Moneypenny, as you're no doubt listening, perhaps you'd take this cable?
内容是:"货品是真的 停 继续进行交易 M上"
"Merchandise appears genuine. Stop. Go ahead with deal. Signed, M. "
我只需要把日期告诉她
Now all I have to do is to tell the girl the date.
十三号吗? 是十四号
The 13th? The 14th.
签证?
Visas?
签证? 谢谢
Visas? Thank you.
我来申请签证
Visa, please.
你的钟准确吗?
Your clock, is it correct?
一向都很准确 当然了
Always. Of course.
抱歉 你说你的钟准确吗?
Excuse me. You did say your clock was correct?
俄罗斯的钟一向都很准确的
Russian clocks are always...
这就是列克托吗? 对
Is this the Lektor? Yes.
戴上它 不过是催泪气而已 我还以为明天才行动呢
Take this. It thought it was for tomorrow.
今天是十三号 现在谈迷信真不是个好时候
Today is the 13th, isn't it? It's a hell of a time to be superstitious.
走吧 快点
Come on. Quickly.
别抬头
Keep your head down.
哇啊
Argh!
回去
Back inside.
这边走 快点
This way. Quickly.
怎么了?  是俄国特工宝士
What's the matter? Benz, the Russian security man.
走吧 没关系的
Come on. Never mind.
赶快!
Hurry. Hurry.
[俄罗斯语]
[ Russian ]
这是其中一间 那是另一间
Here's one of them. And there's the other one.
你的护照 照片跟真人并不吻合
Your passports. The pictures do not do you justice.
很少有这么漂亮的夫妇的
I have rarely seen a handsomer couple.
大卫索美赛伉俪
Mr and Mrs David Somerset.
你叫凯罗琳 凯罗琳 我喜欢这个名字
Your name's Caroline. Caroline. I like that name.
你陪我到德贝夏出差
You're accompanying me on a business trip on our way home.
去探孩子吗? 没有孩子
To our children? No children.
连儿子都没有? 没有的
Not even one little boy? Nyet.
我喜欢大家庭 我这生都在大家庭度过
I like big families. My whole life has been a crusade for larger families.
我知道 坦妮雅 是吗
So I heard. Tania? Yes?
把门锁上 我会敲门三次
Keep the door locked. I'll knock three times.
好的
OK.
我去跟车长见面  你确定他会合作吗?
I'll go see the conductor. You're sure he'll cooperate?
从前我们曾经有交易
We've done business before.
他会在保加利亚边境停下 我儿子会开车接我们
He'll stop the train near the frontier, where my sons will be waiting with a car.
六点整到 小型机场在哪?
We'll be there about six o'clock. And the airstrip?
二十里之外
20 miles.
那是飞往雅典的包机 你明天就会抵达伦敦
The plane is chartered to Athens. You'll be in London tomorrow.
到伦敦后为此而干杯吧
We'll drink to that in London.
我们真的要到英国去
So, we are really on our way to England.
这两天是我们的蜜月期呢
Yes, with a lovely two-day honeymoon before us.
蜜月?我没有衣服穿呢
Honeymoon? And I've nothing to wear.
你的嫁妆 哦 詹姆斯
Your trousseau. Oh, James.
等一下
One moment.
哦 哦 哦 詹姆斯 詹姆斯
Oh. Oh, no. James, James!
看
Oh, look, look.
这样
There.
我会在皮卡迪利大道穿这裙子
I will wear this one in Piccadilly.
不行 他们刚通过了新法例
You won't. They've just passed some new laws there.
你比较近 好吧
You're nearest. Oh, all right.
很迷人
Charming. Charming.
我们到餐车去喝一杯吧
Let's go to the restaurant car, James, for that drink.
好的
Surely.
很迷人
Charming.
晚一点再继续时装秀吧
We'll continue the fashion show later.
一切已安排妥当让我把车停下 我们会从餐车离开 在另一边
Everything's arranged for me to stop the train. We'll get off at the restaurant car.
好 六点整见
Fine. We'll meet you there at six.
要晚一点才行 事情有点复杂
Make it just a little later. But there are complications.
苏联特工宝士在火车上
One of the Russian security men, Benz, he's on the train.
他上车前该没时间联络领事馆
But he wouldn't have had time to contact the consulate.
接下来的两小时我会伴着他 直到是时候下车为止
Just in case, I'll keep him company until it's time to get off.
也许你要我给你介绍 很迷人
Perhaps you'd like me to introduce you. Charming.
查票
Ticket control.
别惊慌 朋友 我们会尽量使你舒服的
Do not be alarmed. We will make you as comfortable as possible.
我可以确定宝士部长的旅程 会更加安全
Now I'm sure Commissar Benz will have a much safer journey.
你没生他的裁缝的气吧?
I'm not mad about his tailor, are you?
伊斯坦堡缺少了你 真的会不一样
You know, James, life in Istanbul will never be the same without you.
餐车上见
See you in the restaurant car.
我这一生非常精彩
I've had a particularly fascinating life.
你有兴趣听听吗?
Would you like to hear about it?
你有兴趣啊?
You would?
你喜欢吗?  喜欢 跟你很搭配
You like it? Yes, it does rather suit you.
我要把其他一切留到英国才穿 现在是下午四点
I will save everything else for England. It is four o'clock, you know.
在下午这样做不太好吧?
This is not kulturny in the afternoon?
即使在度蜜月也不行吗?
Even on a honeymoon?
那我就脱下来吧
Then I will take it off.
我们又再各执一词了
I think we're talking at cross purposes again.
坦妮雅 嗯？
Tania. Mm-hm?
我们还是穿衣服吧
We'd better get dressed now.
干嘛? 快六点了
Why? It's almost six.
那又如何?
So?
下午茶时间到了
Well, it's teatime.
就在这里喝吧
We'll have it in here.
每餐都在这里吃吧 的确是好主意
We'll have all our meals here. Yes, that would be splendid.
不过我跟克林约好了在餐车见面
But I've arranged to meet Kerim in the restaurant car.
你自己去吧 我留下
You go alone. I will stay here.
亲爱的索美赛太太 我们是体面的英国夫妇
My dear Mrs Somerset, we're supposed to be a respectable English couple.
他们会到餐车喝茶
They would certainly have tea in the restaurant.
现在听着
Now listen...
照我的说话办 好吗?  是的 詹姆斯
Just do as I say, will you? Yes, James.
但有些英国习俗应该要改一改
But there are some English customs that are going to be changed.
当然了 亲爱的
But of course, darling.
我的打扮妥当吗? 索美赛先生
Do I look right, Mr Somerset?
好了
Yes...
索美赛太太 真漂亮
Mrs Somerset. How pretty.
索美赛太太
Mr Somerset. Mr Somerset.
你是克林贝的朋友吧?
You are the friend of Kerim Bey? Yes?
出了可怕的状况了 请跟我来
There's been a terrible accident. Please come with me.
不喝茶了吗? 晚一点再喝吧 把门锁上
No tea? Later. Keep the door locked.
他们自伤残杀
They killed each other.
到达翠亚思前 千万别泄露风声 这可是很困难的
This must be kept quiet until Trieste. It will be difficult.
我知道
I'm sure.
克林贝是大人物 结交不少权贵 我肯定他们也会酬谢你的
Kerim Bey had many influential friends. I'm sure they also will reward you.
我会尝试的
I will try.
怎么了?
What is it?
克林死了 死了?
Kerim's dead. Dead?
我要知道真相
I want the truth.
詹姆斯 你弄痛我了! 若你不说 我可以更狠心的
James, you are hurting me. I'll do worse if you don't tell me.
你是奉命行事罢了 他们是谁?
You're doing this under orders, I know. What are they?
我不懂你在说什么? 骗子!
I don't know what you mean. Liar.
即使你杀了我 我也没话可说
Even if you kill me, I can say nothing.
我不晓得克林会死的
I did not know anything like Kerim's death would happen.
不过 抵达伦敦后 我会告诉你
But when we get to England, I tell you.
继续说吧 不要
Go on. Oh, no.
也许他们没把整个计划告诉你 不过快把你所知的都告诉我
Maybe they didn't let you in on all of it, but whatever you do know, tell me.
我只知道我爱你 告诉我
I know I love you, James. I love you. Just tell me.
我爱你 是真的
I love you, I love you, it's true.
当然了
Sure.
贝尔格勒!
Belgrade. Belgrade.
借道
Excuse me.
可以借一根火柴用吗? 我用打火机的
Can I borrow a match? I use a lighter.
那就更好了 直到它们坏掉
Better still. Until they go wrong.
家兄打了电话给我 火车为什么没停下来的?
My brother telephoned me. Why did the train not stop?
我有一个坏消息
Well, I have some bad news.
你爸爸死了
Your father's dead.
是谁干的?告诉我
Who did it? Tell me.
他已经处理好了 对方先死
He took care of that himself. The other man died first.
听好
Now listen...
我需要帮助去要越过 南斯拉夫和翠亚思的边境
I'll need help to get across the frontier between Yugoslavia and Trieste.
请你转达口讯给伦敦的M
I want you to send a message to M in London:
请他从Y分局派人前往扎格拉布 跟我见面
Tell him to send someone from Station Y to meet me in Zagreb.
我会的了
I will.
很好
Good.
哦
Oh.
你 我想你会想要这个的
You'II... I think you'll want these.
这边  谢谢 火车要开了
Monsieur Somerset, le train part. Thank you.
纳许上尉 邦德化名索美赛上路
Captain Nash. Bond, travelling as Somerset.
我的名片
My card.
干嘛这么久才到? 很抱歉 我一小时前才收到M的电报
What kept you? I only got M's wire an hour ago.
我已尽快赶来
I busted every record getting here.
M有什么指示? 他只是叫我跟你和那位女士联络
What were M's orders? To contact you and the lady on the train.
好 这边走
Good. Come this way.
谢谢
Thank you.
她是内子凯罗琳
This is my wife Caroline. Captain Nash.
你好 很高兴认识你
How do you do? I'm so pleased to meet you.
这边走 请坐  谢谢
This way, Nash. Sit down, will you? Thank you.
你来了南斯拉夫很久吗? 三年左右吧
Been long in Yugoslavia? About three years.
工作有趣吗?  有时吧
Interesting work? Yes, sometimes.
你也知道吧 老兄
You know how it is, old man.
你很健壮呢 我努力维持身材
You look very fit, Nash. Yes, I try to keep in shape.
究竟怎么了?
So what's our problem, sir?
我不能冒险带着这东西 在南斯拉夫和翠亚思边境过海关
I can't risk taking this through the customs at the Yugoslav-Trieste border.
再没中途站了 我们得跳车
No stops till then. We'd have to jump off.
你可以帮忙吗? 这里有敌人吗?
Can you get us across? Any of the opposition around?
这方面你不用担心 好 我们办得到的
Not in any condition to worry about. Good. We'll make it.
我对这片土地了如指掌
I know this territory like the back of my hand.
先吃点东西好吗? 我今天只吃过早餐
Do you mind if we have a bite to eat? I've been on the go since breakfast.
把东西留在这里 我们去餐车吧
No, of course not. We'll go to the restaurant car.
凯罗琳 你陪纳许上尉到餐车去 我待会就来
Caroline, you go with Nash. I'll join you there in a few minutes.
就照你的说话办吧 老兄 借光
Whatever you say, old man. Excuse me.
对不起
Excuse me.
老兄 你来了
There you are, old man.
我还担心你出状况了
I was worried something had happened to you.
请问要几成熟？先生 谢谢
Voil? monsieur. Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you.
我要烤比目鱼
I'll have the grilled sole.
这位女士也是 你要什么?
And for madam. What about you, Nash?
听来不错 要三份吧
Yes, that sounds very nice. Make that three of those, will you?
一瓶白酒  我要吉安地酒
I'll have a bottle of Blanc de Blancs. Make mine chianti.
吉安地白酒? 不 是红酒
White chianti? No, the red kind.
好好享用吧 老兄
Well, enjoy your dinner, old man.
我们的问题有解决答案了 很简单的答案
I've got the answer to our problems. Very simple, really.
好
Good.
一小时后就到达边境
We should reach the border in about an hour.
很对不起 索美赛太太 我真是笨手笨脚的
I'm terribly sorry, Mrs Somerset. That was clumsy of me.
服务员 先生
Waiter. Monsieur.
服务员 马上就来，先生
Waiter. Tout de suite, monsieur.
对不起 谢谢 你会发觉翠亚思是个蛮有趣的地方
Excuse me.  Merci. You'll find Trieste quite interesting.
当然 总比不上伦敦
Of course, it's not London.
干杯 干杯
Cheerio. Cheerio.
我有点不舒服
I don't feel very well.
我的头
My head...
太太要昏过去了 让她进来
The lady's come over faint. Bring her in here.
我怎么了?
What is wrong with me?
到隔壁去吧  我想她累坏了
Let's go next door. Exhaustion, I'd say.
这是什么 你在她的饮料里下了什么药?
What was it, the stuff you put in her drink?
水合氯醛 快速见效 药性温和
Chloral hydrate. Quick, but mild.
还有呢? 放轻松 007
And? Take it easy, 007.
我的逃亡路线只能带一个人走 你要那个女孩还是解码器?
My escape route's only for one. What are you after, the girl or the Lektor?
好吧
All right.
你有什么计划呢? 我用地图解释吧
What is your plan? Explain it better on a map. All right?
我们在这里 看到了吗?
Now, we're here, you see?
这里有一条陡坡 火车会慢下来
When we reach there, there's a steep gradient. The train slows down there.
我们封锁这路线 走到大道去 在那里乘车
We'll block the line, make for that main road, pick up a car.
其实那是一辆货车
A truck, in fact.
距离这里必定有二十里
That must be about 20 miles from here...
别动
Keep still.
跪下来
All right, now. Get up on your knees.
双手放在口袋里 别动
Put your hands in your pockets. Keep them there.
用红酒来配鱼肉 我早该料到
Red wine with fish. That should have told me something.
你知道喝哪种酒才适合 可是现在跪着的人是你
You may know the right wines, but you're the one on your knees.
老兄 感觉如何?
How does it feel, old man?
老兄? 是你们在情报科的称号吧?
Old man? Is that what you chaps in SMERSH call each other?
情报科?
SMERSH?
当然了 是幽灵党
Of course. SPECTRE.
原来不是俄国在耍花招
It wasn't a Russian show at all.
你让我们互相猜忌 对吗?
You've been playing us off against each other, haven't you?
清真寺的俄国特工是幽灵党杀的
It was SPECTRE who killed the Russian agent in the mosque.
是你干的吧? 嗯
You? Mm-hm.
克林和另外的人呢? 嗯
Kerim and the other man? Mm-hm.
还有纳什?
And Nash?
我不介意谈话
I don't mind talking.
看着詹姆斯邦德 发现自己是个大蠢才 实在刺激
I get a kick out of watching James Bond find out what a bloody fool he's been.
我们可是内行呢 邦德先生
We're pros, Mr Bond.
你在东京的同事临死前 把识别密码招供出来
We sweated your recognition code out of one of your men in Tokyo before he died.
我们一直密切监视着你 我一直是你的守护天使
I've been keeping tabs on you. I've been your guardian angel.
在吉普赛营中救了你一命
Saved your life at the Gypsy camp.
哦 是的 真是感激不尽
Oh, yes. I'm much obliged.
你拿到解码器前 我们一直保着你的性命
We were keeping you alive until you could get us the Lektor.
你要我把它拱手奉上 真聪明
So you had me deliver it on a plate. That's brilliant.
继续说吧 我听得很着迷呢
Go on. I'm fascinated.
既然解码器已到手  你和那女子都可以牺牲了
Now that we've got it, you and the girl are expendable.
在这里至翠亚思之间
Between here and Trieste.
那女子
The girl?
不是幽灵党的一份子吗? 不是
Isn't she working for SPECTRE, too? No.
她以为自己在为祖国服务呢
She thinks she's doing it all for Mother Russia.
她听从克莱普上校的指挥
She takes her orders from Colonel Klebb.
俄国人克莱普 情报科行动组组长
Rosa Klebb's Russian. Head of operations for SMERSH.
从前才是
Was.
她是幽灵党的人了 那女孩并不知情
Klebb works for SPECTRE now. The girl doesn't know that.
为何还要把她干掉? 这是命令
Then why kill her? Orders.
计划还不只于此的
That's only half of it, old man.
这里有一卷胶卷 将会在她的手袋里出现
Here's a roll of film. She'll have this in her handbag.
这封信则会在你身上出现
And on you, they'll find this letter.
是她写的 说因她帮过你
It's from her, threatening to give the film to the press
而必须娶她 否则她就公开这影片
unless you marry her for helping you get the Lektor.
什么影片呢?
What film?
在你下榻的结婚套房里拍下的
Taken in the bridal suite at your hotel.
那个女孩和你都懵然不知
Something else the girl didn't know about. Or you.
只有变态的才能想出这种计策
It must be a pretty sick collection of minds to dream up a plan like that.
你可以想像到头条吗?
Can't you see the headlines?
"英国特工谋杀俄国女特工 自戕而死"
"British agent murders beautiful Russian spy, then commits suicide."
告诉我 你是从哪所疯人院中逃出来的?
Tell me, which lunatic asylum did they get you out of?
别为难自己
Don't make it tougher on yourself.
我的指示是把你干掉 把解码器运送回去
My orders are to kill you and deliver the Lektor.
要用什么方式由我作主
How I do it is my business.
你会觉得痛不欲生 他们给了你多少报酬?
It'll be slow and painful. How much are they paying you?
关你什么事? 我们把酬金加倍
What's it to you? We'll double it.
你敢用名誉担保吗?
Your word of honour?
英国绅士的名誉
As an English gentleman?
第一枪不会干掉你
The first one won't kill you.
第二枪也是
Not the second.
第三枪也不会
Not even the third.
直至你爬过来吻我的脚 我才会杀了你
Not till you crawl over here and you kiss my foot.
给我一支烟好吗? 你休想
How about a cigarette? Not a chance.
我付钱
I'll pay for it.
用什么付呢? 五十个一镑金币
What with? 50 gold sovereigns.
在哪? 在上面 我的皮箱里
Where are they? Up there, in my case.
你拿出来
You show me.
给你 香烟在哪?
Here you are. What about that cigarette?
把那些东西放下
Throw 'em down there.
其他公事包里还有吗?
Any more in the other case?
我想应该有 那是个标准配备 让我看看
I should imagine so. It's standard kit. I'll have a look.
双手放回口袋里!
Put your hands back in your pockets.
别伸出来
Keep them there.
你不需要这个的了
You won't be needing this...
老兄
old man.
坦妮雅 快起来
Tania. Wake up.
快起来 否则我不管你了
Wake up, or I'll leave you behind.
坦妮雅 快起来 否则我不管你了 你听到吗?
Tania, wake up or I'll leave you behind, do you hear me?
别丢下我 永远不要离开我
Don't leave me. Never leave me.
坦妮雅 这是纳许的逃走路线 明白吗?
Tania, this is Nash's escape route. You understand?
我们得从这下车 拿着 来吧
We've got to get off here. Take this. Come on.
一定要走到火车的另一边 到下面去
We must get to the other side of the train. Under here.
葛兰 你在哪?
Grant, where are you? Grant?
对不起
Excuse me.
别跑走了
Now, don't run away.
快点!
Come on.
快点!否则我把你留在这里 跟我一起留下来吧
Come on, or I'll leave you here. Stay here with me.
在这里躺一下吧 早上就没事了
Sleep it off in there. You'll feel better in the morning.
起来
Come on, wake up.
把货车轰掉
Try and straddle the truck.
我去引开他们 你躲到货车下面
I'll get them away from here. You hide under the truck.
我确定他们一架飞机失踪了
I'd say one of their aircraft is missing.
坦妮雅
Tania.
拿着 把绳索解开 好的
Here, take this, and cast the rope off. All right.
钥匙在哪?
Where's the key? Where's the key?
在外套的口袋里
In my coat. In the pocket.
出来 快点 上船
All right, get out. Move. In the boat.
你会游泳吗?
Do you swim?
你来掌舵 请到这边来
Take the wheel. This way, please.
小心阶梯
Mind the step.
今天你真倒霉
Just isn't your day, is it?
我们要到哪去呢? 威尼斯
Where are we going? Venice.
看看那储物柜内有什么 好吗?
Take a look at that locker, will you?
有航海图、手枪和几枚照明弹
Charts, pistol, some flares.
航海图给我
Give me those charts.
对 我们在此 伊斯特里亚附近
Yes, we're here, near Istria.
还有很多燃料 走运的话 明早就会到达
We've got plenty of fuel. With luck we should be there by morning.
翠亚思的火车上发现了三具尸体 其中一个是葛兰
Three man were found dead on the train at Trieste. One of them was Grant.
五号 你有什么高见呢?
What have you to say, Number Five?
他是克莱普的人选 她的手下失败了
He was Klebb's choice. Her people failed.
你是策划人 他们只是奉命行事
It was your plan. They followed it implicitly.
没可能的 计划完美无瑕
Impossible. It was perfect.
除了一件事 他们要对付的是邦德
Except for one thing: They were dealing with Bond.
跟克朗斯汀比起来 邦德是什么东西啊?
Who is Bond compared with Kronsteen?
一点没错 你有何高见 三号?
Exactly. What have you to say to that, Number Three?
邦德还没死 解码器还没到手
Bond is still alive and the Lektor is not yet in our possession.
我跟俄国人协议了 要把它归还
I have already negotiated with the Russians to return it to them.
价钱也谈好了 幽灵党是言出必行的
We've agreed a price. And SPECTRE always delivers what it promises.
组织的兴亡 在于我们能否遵守诺言
Our whole organisation depends on our keeping those promises.
我曾警告过你 我们不会容忍失败
I warned you. We do not tolerate failure,
三号 你知道惩罚是什么了吧?
Number Three. You know the penalty.
知道 一号
Yes, Number One.
我们的规矩很简单 若你失败了
Our rules are very simple. If you fail...
十二秒 终有一天要发明更快见效的毒液
12 seconds. One day we must invent a faster-working venom.
三号 是的 长官
Number Three. Yes?
我不希望跟俄国人说 还要再延期
I do not wish to tell the Russians there will be another delay.
不会延期的了 还有时间
There will be no delay, Number One. There's still time.
我们要走哪条路? 最短的一条
Which way are we going? The shortest route.
穿过那两座山 沿着海岸直驶
Which is between those two mountains and straight along the coast.
邦德先生!
Ahoy, Mr Bond. Ahoy, Mr Bond.
举手
Heave to. Heave to.
你已经被包围了!
You're trapped, Mr Bond. You're trapped.
你逃不掉的!
You cannot escape. You cannot escape.
枪榴弹队 准备开火!
Prepare to fire.
我们要穿过来了! 绿色幽灵 让开!
We're coming through. Pull over, SPECTRE Green. Get out of the way!
快让路 开枪警告他们
Give them a warning shot.
枪榴弹队 开火!
Rifle grenade, fire.
机关枪队 开火!
Forward machine gun, fire.
红色幽灵 射击的距离太近了
You're firing too close.
绿色幽灵 射击的距离太近了
SPECTRE Red, SPECTRE Green, you're firing too close.
你们要拦截 而不是击沉他们
You're trying to stop them, not to sink them.
你来掌舵
Here, take the wheel.
慢下来
Slow down.
所有船只 慢下来
Slow down. Slow down all boats.
绿色 我们掩护你 开到他们的旁边
Green, go alongside while we keep you covered.
举起手来 邦德先生!  你干嘛要放弃呢?
Hands up, Mr Bond.
没有油桶 可以开快一点  手枪给我
Without the drums we can go faster. Hand me the Very pistol.
别放下手 我们派船来接你
Keep your hands up. We're sending a boat along to take you off.
英国有句谚语说:有烟必有火
There's a saying in England, "Where there's smoke, there's fire."
绿色幽灵 快改变航道!
Green, change your course. Go astern.
所有船只 快把火药抛弃! 快离开船
All boats, throw out your ammunition. Get rid of it, quick.
离开船
Get rid of it.
跳!
Jump.
快跳!
Quickly jump.
别走开!
Don't go away.
好
Yes.
谢了 叫他等等 可以吗? 请你派服务员来搬行李 谢谢
Oh, thanks. Tell him to wait, will you? And send up a porter for the luggage.
进来
Avanti.
可以整理了吗 夫人? 可以啊 请吧
Permesso, signore? Si Prego.
还有 把电话接到英国领事 谢谢
And also get me the British Consul. Thank you.
我找麦斯威尔先生 詹姆斯邦德
Yes? Oh, Mr Maxwell, please. James Bond.
詹姆斯 我们要错过班机了
James, we will miss the plane. And we will...
是保罗吗? 我是邦德 我们快要走了 我想向你道谢
Hello, Paul? Bond here. I wanted to thank you for everything.
请通知公司说我我们要回来了 那是什么?
Signal the office we're on our way back, will you? What was that?
别动那个 我自己会拿
Here, leave that. I'll take it.
什么？哦 不 余下的只是例行公事罢了 很多次
What? Oh, no. Should be routine from here on in.
你说什么? 克莱普
Hello, what was that you were saying? Klebb.
詹姆斯 你还在吗? 喂?
James, you still there? Hello?
罗曼诺娃 开门
Romanova, the door.
罗曼诺娃
Romanova!
拿着
Take this.
可怕的女人
Horrible woman.
对 她的脚劲还真厉害
Yes. She's had her kicks.
给你 它可能会再派上用场
Here you are. In case you ever need it again.
对 必须对政府公物负责
Oh, yes. All government property has to be accounted for.
但正如我所说过的 我们不见得要在办公时间内合作
But as I said before, we won't always work on the company's time, will we?
不要
No.
你检点一点 有人在拍摄我们呢
James, behave yourself. We are being filmed.
噢 别再来一次
Oh, not again.
他没说谎呢
He was right, you know.
这是什么?  我示范给你看吧
What is it? I'll show you.